Ajeeth kumar G

Full Stack Developer

≥ ajeethkumar.vishnupriya@gmail.com

L +91 6382862595

Enthusiastic and reliable developer with a strong knowledge of web development with 1.6+ years of industry experience as part of a computer program development team.

Skills Javascript Express-js HTML Node-js CSS MongoDB Java Bootstrap React AWS Git-hub React-Bootstrap Firebase **Projects** Pizza order Application Instagram-clone Whatsapp-clone Netflix-clone Rental Application **Project Description**

Server-side

- Testing route api's using postman.
- For Authentication purpose, I have used bcryptjs and jsonwebtoken.
- CORS for security mechanism.
- To create environment variables, I have used dotenv.
- Express for Nodejs web application framework to manage servers and routes
- DB used Mongodb Atlas for cloud level data storge
- · Created schemas and models using mongoose
- Configured email services using Nodemailer
- For speedy development of nodejs application I have used Nodemon which automatically starts the server once saved
- Razorpay for payment gateway
- To check the correctness of the fragments of code I have utilized validator
- For real time communication layer between server and client, I have achieved it instantly using Pusher
- · For movie database I have used TMDB Api's

Client-side

- Building interactive user interface quickly using ReactJs
- For light weight CSS Framework Material UI, Bootstrap and React-bootstrap
- To simplify redux development I have used ReduxJs toolkit
- Antd to create elegant components
- · Axios for HTTP request handling
- To manage forms with complex validation with ease Formik has been used
- Moment to display date as per localization
- To display dates using calendar dialog format React Datepicker has been used
- React Icons to add Icons
- · Advanced state management using React-redux
- Dynamic routing in web application using React-router-dom
- For toast notification React-toastify
- · React hooks for reusability, readability and testability
- For Authentication Firebase has been used
- To send emails using client-side applications like React I have used Emailjs

Experience

Graduate Engineering Trainee, SFL(TVS)

2017 - 2018

Associate Professional, DXC Technology.

2022 - Current

Education

B.E-Mechanical Engineering,
Nehru Institute of Technology, Coimbatore.

2013 - 2016

Diploma In Mechanical Engineering, Rajagopal Polytechnical College, Vellore. 2010 - 2013

Certifications

 Certification of Full Stack Development in MERN Stack from GUVI Geek Networks, IITM Research Park

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is true